JEFFREY GICHUKI

GAME DEVELOPER

CONTACT



https://briskwoods.github.io/



julian.gichuki@gmail.com



https://github.com/Briskwoods



Jeffrey Gichuki - LinkedIn



Nairobi, Kenya

SKILLS

Game Development: Unity, Unreal Engine, Godot, C#, C++, GDScript.

Web Development: HTML5, PhP, Laravel, Wordpress, MySQL, Bootstrap, NPM

SCM: Git, Github, GitLab

Software Development: Java, Python, C#,

Professional Skills: Team Collaboration, Team Organisation, Creativity, Modular Design Principles, Logical and Analytical

thinking, Communication

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Informatics and Computer Science

Strathmore University

2017 - 2021

Awarded Second Upper Class Honours with a GPA of 3.02

CERTIFICATIONS

Crazyhubs Graduate - the Hyper-Casual Gaming Accelerator (South Africa)

CrazyLabs

Nov 2021 - Mar 2022

Credential ID 1121170005

LANGUAGES

English
Swahili
Japanese

PROFILE

I am experienced Game Programmer with a deep love for narrative driven Games, their Development and Design. With an appreciation for clean code practices, making code as simple as possible and experience in Full Stack Development I am ready and equipped to jump across Game Development softwares. The simpler the code the better.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mekan Games Ltd.

Nairobi, Kenya.

Team Lead and Senior Unity Developer

Aug 2022 - Present

- Consistently achieved a CPI of under 0.87\$ across multiple projects after promotion.
- Ideated, Iterated, Designed and Developed multple games with over 28% retention on projects that went into the Retention Phase of testing.
- Ideated, Designed, Developed, Iterated, Collaborated, Prototyped, Polished and Optimised over 84 in-house concepts across two teams, leveraging iterative processes to achieve diverse levels of success.
- Involved heavily in teaching clean code practices and file organisation structures utilised within the company.

Unity Developer

Apr 2021 - Aug 2022

- Part of the core team that Ideated, Designed, Developed, Iterated and Maintained The President mobile game that achieved over 20 Million combined Downloads globally across Android and iOS Devices.
- Achieved a stable CPI of under 0.35\$ on iOS and 0.43\$ on Android over a period
 of 6 months as the game was in iteration.
- Achieved a consistent Retention of above 38% on The President across platforms.

Unity Developer Intern

Apr 2021 - Aug 2022

 Developed 2 projects with CTR's of 2.5% on the first and 3.8% on the second project.

Virdane Labs Ltd.

Nairobi, Kenya

Founder

April 2020 - Present

- Ideated, Designed and Developed a game, Rachel's Grasp, as part of a Research
 Project to determine whether Games can be used to teach players methods of
 understanding and better dealing with Anxiety Disorders through
 implementation of therapy techniques mixed with Narrative Design and Game
 Development.
- Prototyping and Developing Game Mechanics and tools for both 2D and 3D game platforms.

JEFFREY GICHUKI

GAME DEVELOPER

CONTACT WORK EXPERIENCE https://briskwoods.github.io/ **Kunta Content** Nairobi, Kenya. julian.gichuki@gmail.com **Senior Game Developer** https://github.com/Briskwoods • Developed, Prototyped and Iterated on unreleased project. Jeffrey Gichuki - LinkedIn **Game Development Advisor** Nairobi, Kenya · Advised and overlooked over the design and development of an unreleased mobile game. AWARDS **Jiwe Studios** () Games Industry Africa Awards 2022 -Nairobi, Kenya. Game of the Year - The President. Video Game Developer Intern (Mekan Games Ltd.) • Fullfilled roles in the Wrtiting, Design, Development, Testing and Publishing () Games Industry Africa Awards 2022 departments of the company on inhouse projects. Most Impactful Video game - The President.(Mekan Games Ltd.) **Tezza Business Solutions Ltd.** Games Industry Africa Awards 2022 -Nairobi, Kenya. Debut of the Year - The President. **Developer Intern** (Mekan Games Ltd.)

REFERENCES

Reference Name

+254727522222

evanskiragu@mekangames.com

Jun 2022 - Feb 2023

Apr 2022 - May 2022

Feb 2021 - Apr 2021

Jan 2020 - Mar 2020

• Organised and Executed workshops to expose and educate University Students on how to use Unity at Strathmore University.

Unity Technologies

Nairobi, Kenya.

Student Ambassador

Jan 2019 - May 2021

• Organised and Executed workshops to expose and educate University Students on how to use Unity at Strathmore University.